Put a cat in a box with a radioactive
atom. Add a radiation detector that
triggers the release of poisonous
cyanide gas. Now, although it was only
meant as a thought experiment,
Schrödinger helpfully notes this device
must be secured against direct
interference by the cat.
Anyway, the whole point of the
experiment is to magnify the state of
the atom up to the state of something
macroscopic and tangible. He could have
picked anything. It didn't have to be
alive, but Schrödinger selected a cat.
If the atom decays, the detector detects
radiation, releases the poison, and the
cat dies. If the atom doesn't decay, the
detector doesn't detect radiation,
poison is not released, and the cat
remains alive. Since the state [music]
of the cat and detector apparatus are
directly tied to the state of the atom,
we say they are entangled.
Where things get weird is that according
to quantum mechanics, the state of the
atom does not have to be either decayed
or not decayed. Generally, it's in a
superposition of both, decayed and not
decayed at the same time, assuming no
measurements have been made. This
superposition state of the atom gets
[music] entangled with the detector and
then the cat. So, after some time, the
wave function of everything inside the
box is in a superposition of the atom
has not decayed, poison not released,
cat alive state and the atom has
decayed, poison released, cat [music]
dead state. So, according to quantum
mechanics, the cat really is both alive
and dead at the same time. Only when we
open the box and make a measurement does
the wave function collapse and the cat
actually becomes either dead or alive.